Guide to the "Select Issues in Biomedical Ethics" [videorecording]
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
"Select Issues in Biomedical Ethics" [videorecording]
1998
V0193
Stanford Channel (Television station: Stanford, Calif.)
1.25 Linear feet 10 videotapes (VHS)
Telecourse taught by Ernle Young, professor of medicine at the Stanford Medical School, and Simon Whitney, a Fellow at the Center for Biomedical Ethics; subjects include genetics and the Human Genome Project, emergency medicine, physician-assisted suicide, managed care, and organ transplantation. Guest speakers include Henry Greeley, Bruce Feldstein, Fred Marcus, David Spiegel, and Alain Enthoven.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, 1999.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Stanford Channel is managed by Stanford University's Information Technology Systems and Services (ITSS), specifically Communication Services. Its broadcasts include telecourses, original programs, lectures, conferences, and Stanford sports events.
Description of the Collection
Telecourse taught by Ernle Young, professor of medicine at the Stanford Medical School, and Simon Whitney, a Fellow at the Center for Biomedical Ethics; subjects include genetics and the Human Genome Project, emergency medicine, physician-assisted suicide, managed care, and organ transplantation. Guest speakers include Henry Greeley, Bruce Feldstein, Fred Marcus, David Spiegel, and Alain Enthoven.
Access Terms
Enthoven, Alain C., 1930-; Feldstein, Bruce.; Feldstein, Bruce.; Greeley, Henry.; Greeley, Henry.; Human Genome Project--Moral and ethical aspects.; Human Genome Project. -- General subdivision--Moral and ethical aspects.;; Marcus, Fred.; Marcus, Fred.; Spiegel, David, 1945-; Stanford Channel (Television station: Stanford, Calif.); Whitney, Simon.; Whitney, Simon.; Young, Ernle W. D.; Assisted suicide--Moral and ethical aspects.; Emergency medicine--Moral and ethical aspects.; Managed care plans (Medical care)--Moral and ethical aspects.; Medical ethics.; Videorecordings.
Collection Contents
- Videos (Box 1)
- Principles of Medical Ethics and the Duties Deriving from Them, March 1998; V193.1 (Box 1)
- Ethical Issues in Genetics and the Human Genome Project, 1998 Apr; V193.2 (Box 1)
- Ethical Issues in Genetics and the Human Genome Project, Henry Greely, 1998 Apr; V193.3 (Box 1)
- Emergency Ethics in Medicine, 1998 Apr; V193.4 (Box 1)
- Ethics in Emergency Medicine, Bruce Feldstein, 1998 Apr; V193.5 (Box 2)
- Physician-Assisted Suicide: Ethical Issues, 1998 May; V193.6 (Box 2)
- Physician-Assisted Suicide, 1998 May; V193.7A (Box 2)
- Physician-Assisted Suicide, Fred Marcus and David Spiegel, 1998 May; V193.7B (Box 2)
- Managed Care: Ethical Issues, Alain Enthoven, 1998 May; V193.8 (Box 2)
- Ethical Issues in Organ Transplantation and Course Review, 1998 May; V193.9 (Box 2)